rivs.com 2015-05-27

# Privacy Policy | RIVS Digital Interviews | Video Interviews | Job Applicant Management | Efficient Hiring

#### This Privacy Policy was last updated on November, 11th 2013

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how RIVS, Inc. (“RIVS,” “we” or “us”) collect, use and share personally identifiable information of visitors of our web site [www.rivs.com](https://www.rivs.com/www.rivs.com) (the “Site”) and users of our digital interview application (the “Services”). The use of information collected through the Services shall be limited to the purpose of providing those Services to our customers. By using the Site and/or Services, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

RIVS has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal.

The TRUSTe program covers our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our website, www.rivs.com and our Platform. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged RIVS.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

RIVS has committed to work with the European Data Protection Authorities to ensure our practices are compliant with the E.U. Safe Harbor framework. Should you have any questions or complaints in regards to our privacy policy or practices please contact us at [support@rivs.com](mailto:support@rivs.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you may contact the [European Data Protection Authorities here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/). 

#### U.S.--E.U. Safe Harbor

RIVS complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. RIVS has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view RIVS’ certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

#### Information We Collect and How We Use It

You can generally visit the Site without revealing any personally identifiable information about yourself. We do not collect personal information from our Site visitors without the Site visitor providing us with this information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

If you request to receive company or product information or request an online demonstration of the Services, you will be asked to complete the online demo request form on our Site that asks for your name, title, e-mail address, company name, and phone number. We use the information from the request form to deliver the requested information and/or provide you with the online demonstration of the Services.

In order to become a registered user of the Services, RIVS requires you to create a user account. To register for a user account, you must provide the following personally identifiable information: 

  * If you are an employer, you must provide your company’s name and e-mail address of a contact at your company.
  * If you are an employee of an employer, you must provide your name, e-mail address, and phone.
  * If you are a jobseeker, the information that you need to provide is determined by the employer who is using RIVS to review candidates for their job opening or similar opportunity

Providing any additional information beyond what is required at registration is optional. 

#### Aggregate Information

RIVS may also automatically collect and analyze information about your general usage of the Site and Services. When you perform certain actions using the Services, RIVS may track your usage patterns to see what features of the Site and Services you commonly use, Site traffic volume, frequency of visits, type and time of transactions, type of browser, browser language, IP address and operating system, and statistical information about types of jobs offered and qualifications of jobseekers. RIVS will collect, track and analyze such information in an aggregate manner that does not personally identify you. This aggregate data may be used by RIVS and third party vendors to assist RIVS in operating the Site and the Services and provided to other third parties to enable them to better understand the operation of RIVS’ business, but such information will be in aggregate form only and it will not contain personally identifiable data. RIVS may also gather information about you (that you voluntarily submit to RIVS) when you log-in to the Services, provide feedback to RIVS and/or send or receive communications regarding the Services.

RIVS may use your personally identifiable information to register you to use the Services and provide you with the Services; verify your authority to enter the Site and access the Services; notify you of Services updates; improve the content and general administration of the Site and the Services; provide you with notices regarding the Services and other services that you have purchased or may wish to purchase in the future; and to send you targeted advertising. RIVS does not provide e-mail addresses or any of your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes.

#### Behavioral Targeting/ Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

#### Children

RIVS recognizes the privacy interests of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. This Site is not intended for children under the age of 13 and we endeavor not to collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. RIVS targets its Services and this Site to adults and not to children under 13.

#### Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

#### Information Related to Data Collected through RIVS Services

RIVS collects information under the direction of its customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes except when RIVS uses its services for its own hiring needs. Part of the Services offered by our employer customers includes providing notice to their employees and job-seekers concerning how their personal information is collected and used. The interview or job application that an employee or other job-seeker submits will be provided only to the specific potential employers that you select when you apply for jobs online. Other employers and recruiters will not have access to your resume or job application unless and until you want them to.

RIVS engages vendors and service agencies to assist us in providing the Services to you, and RIVS will need to share your personally identifiable information (and data generated by cookies and beacons) with these vendors and service agencies. The vendors and service agencies do not receive any right to use your personally identifiable information beyond what is necessary to perform its obligations to provide the Services to you. Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, RIVS will not disclose personally identifiable information to third parties, including, but not limited to, companies affiliated with RIVS, without your consent.

#### Choice and Access to Data Controlled by our Customers

RIVS has no direct relationship with the individual employees and job-seekers whose personal data it processes on our behalf of our customers. Individuals applying or interviewing for jobs with employers that are RIVS customers are identified by their email address that associates all applications and interviews for that individual with that email address. The individual can access their My Interviews page at the Site and transmit requests to the employers to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data in an application. The employer is responsible for complying with the individual’s request. In accordance with applicable law, RIVS retains an archive copy of the individual’s data for the period prescribed by such law. Additionally, if you are an employee or job-seeker and would no longer like to be contacted by a particular employer or employers, please contact them directly to resolve your concern.

#### Information Disclosure for Legal and Other Exceptional Reasons

We may also disclose your personally identifiable information: (a) if we are required to do so by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, regulation or other government authority or otherwise in cooperation with an investigation of a governmental authority, (b) to enforce the RIVS Terms of Use or Master Subscription Agreement or (c) to protect our rights and the safety of users of our Site and our Services. In addition, we may transfer your personally identifiable information to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which RIVS participates or to a purchaser of all or substantially all of RIVS assets to which this Site relates. In this case, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

We may also disclose your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us .

#### Data Retention

RIVS retains personal information and the personal data we process on behalf of our customers for as long as needed to provide the Services to customers, job-seekers and employees enrolled in those Services. We will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements with customers, and/or the period required by laws in applicable jurisdictions.

#### Updating, Correcting and Deleting Your Information

RIVS provides an individual that supplies information on the Site with the ability to correct and request the deletion of any of the personally identifiable information that was entered into their profile on the Site. To correct or delete any information in a Site profile, an individual may contact RIVS by e-mailing our customer support at [support@rivs.com](mailto:support@rivs.com). We will respond to the request within 30 days. Alternatively, you may send a letter with your requested changes, corrections or deletions to the following address:

By Mail:  
RIVS, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Policy  
112 S. Sangamon St, Suite 400  
Chicago, IL 60607  

When an individual terminates their Employer account on the Site, we will remove their profile from the Site. Information supplied by an employee or job seeker in an application or resume submitted to an employer that is a RIVS customer is treated as described above in the section “Choice and Access to Data Controlled by our Customers.”

#### Opt-Out Preferences

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, if you wish to opt-out of receiving these messages, you may follow the unsubscribe procedure provided in the email. 

#### Transfer of Information

Your personally identifiable information collected on this Site and through the Services is stored and processed in the United States where RIVS (or its agents) currently maintain its computer systems. Your personal data will be processed by us in the United States where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Union. If you create a user account with the Site as a visitor from outside the United States, by using the Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy and you consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States, which may not offer an equivalent level of protection of that required in the European Union or certain other countries, and to the processing of that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Cookies & Beacons

Cookies are files sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser while a persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. RIVS’ persistent and session ID cookies are used to identify unique visitors and to provide a personalized user experience. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use our application and some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

We also employ a software technology called Web Beacons that help us better manage content on our Site and on the sites that we maintain for our customers by informing us what content is effective. Beacons are bits of code that function similar to cookies. RIVS’ beacons are embedded in outgoing emails and generate a call back to the RIVS server when such emails are opened. RIVS uses beacons to track the status of sent emails including job or interview invitations sent as RIVS. The use of cookies by our Vendors and Service Agencies is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. 

#### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. RIVS employs procedural and technological measures to protect your personally identifiable information. These measures are reasonably designed to help protect your personally identifiable information from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. RIVS may use software, secure socket layer technology (SSL) encryption, password protection, firewalls, internal restrictions and other security measures to help prevent unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information. However, RIVS cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat these measures or use your personally identifiable information for improper purposes. Therefore, you should be aware that when you voluntarily display or distribute personally identifiable information, that information could be collected and used by others. RIVS is not responsible for the unauthorized use by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available publicly. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@rivs.com](mailto:support@rivs.com).

#### Links to Other Websites

The Site may provide links to third party web sites or resources not associated with RIVS, and over which RIVS does not have control (“External Web Sites”). Such links do not constitute an endorsement by RIVS of the External Web Sites, the content displayed therein, or the persons or entities associated therewith. You acknowledge that RIVS is only providing these links as a convenience, and you agree that RIVS is not responsible for the content of such External Web Sites. Your use of External Web Sites is subject to the respective terms of use and privacy policies located on the linked to External Web Sites. RIVS does not store any information (user name, password) used to access these External Web Sites.

#### Our Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@rivs.com](mailto:support@rivs.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

#### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@rivs.com](mailto:support@rivs.com).

#### Single Sign-On

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

#### Other Social Media Features and Web-Apps

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, Google+ button, Twitter and Linkedin Share button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

#### Material Changes

RIVS reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. RIVS will post the revised Privacy Policy on this Site located at <https://www.rivs.com/privacy/> and will either send a notice to the e-mail address that you specified in your registration and/or post notice of the change so it is visible when users log-on for the first time prior to said changes taking effect so that you are always aware of what personal information RIVS may collect and how RIVS may use this information. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued use of the Site and/or Services will be subject to the then-current Privacy Policy.

#### Contact Us

We welcome your comments or questions concerning our Privacy Policy. If you would like to contact RIVS regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by emailing us at [support@rivs.com](mailto:support@rivs.com), or by mail

RIVS, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Policy  
112 S. Sangamon St, Suite 400  
Chicago, IL 60607
